Plath mss. VI, 1962-1973 LMC 2766
Lilly Library
Plath mss. VI
1962-1973
Lilly Library
Plath, Sylvia, 1932-1963
LMC 2766
1 Box 1 standard
The Plath mss. VI, ca. 1962-1973, consist of early letters, newspaper clippings, and ephemera of poet Sylvia Plath.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Sylvia Plath (1932-1963) was an American writer and poet. Plath was born in Boston, Massachusetts, and was educated at Smith College (MA) and Newnham College (Cambridge), the latter on a Fulbright Fellowship. While in England, Plath met and married Ted Hughes. Plath returned to the United States in 1957 to teach at Smith College with Hughes, who taught at the University of Massachusetts, Amherst. Plath and Hughes returned to England in 1959 where they remained until Plath's death in 1963.
Scope and Content Note
The Plath mss. VI, ca. 1962-1973, consist of early letters, newspaper clippings, and ephemera of poet Sylvia Plath. Included are original Plath-related letters to William Clair, poet and critic, former editor of the literary magazine Voyages. Other correspondents include Ted Hughes, Anne Sexton, Elizabeth Drew, Katherine Ann Porter, Alfred Young Fisher, Ann Williams, Peter Davidson, Frank Murphy, and Ellen Stoianoff.
Related Material
See Plath mss., Plath mss. II, Plath mss. III, Plath mss. IV, Plath mss. V, Plath mss. VII, Plath mss. VIII, Plath mss. IX, Plath mss. X, Plath mss. XI, located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Also see the Guide to the Sylvia Plath Materials in the Lilly Library.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 2012.
Women; Plath, Sylvia
- Autism, Autoeroticism, Auto-da-fe: The Tragic Poetry of Sylvia Plath The Hollins Critic, Volume 10, Number 1, February 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Michele Murray Okay, Sylvia Plath Was Good, but Not That Good The National Observer, Sep. 30, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- William F. Claire 'The Bell Jar' Reviewed by William F. Claire, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Thomas Lask A Kind of Heroism The New York Times, Jun. 8, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Richard Howard Five Poets untitled, Volume 101, Number 6, Mar. 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Gene Baro Varied Quintet The New York Times Book Review, Jun. 26, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Sylvia Plath Early unpublished poems The Times Literary Supplement, Number 3518, Jul. 31, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Sylvia Plath Ten Poems Encounter, Volume 21, Number 4, Oct. 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Oberg, Arthur K., ALS, 1 page, Apr. 29 [undated] (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Oberg, Arthur K.Sylvia Plath and the New Decadence The Chicago Review, Volume 20, Number 1, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Sklarew, Myra For Sylvia Plath, undated, ca. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Sklarew, Myra. TSL, 1 page, undated, ca. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- William F. Claire That Rare, Random Descent: The Poetry and Pathos of Sylvia Plath (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Sylvia Plath November Graveyard Mademoiselle, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Sylvia Plath Sunday at the Mintons Mademoiselle, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Mary Handy Judges Hear Glasscock Poetry Contestants The Christian Science Monitor, Volume 47, Number 120, Apr. 18, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- William F. Claire Poetry By Sylvia Plath Shows Serious Control untitled, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- William F. Claire A Summer of Her Discontent The Washington Post, Apr. 13, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- New Poetry 1964: Critical Quarterly Poetry Supplement, Volume 6, Number 5 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- William F. Claire That Rare and Random Descent: the Poetry and Pathos of Sylvia Plath The Antioch Review, Volume 26, Number 4, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- William F. Claire Remembering Sylvia Plath While Watching Smith College Girls Row At Paradise Pond; Northampton, Massachusetts, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- John Press Two Poets Punch, Mar. 31, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Stephen Spender Warnings from the Grave The New Republic, Volume 154, Number 25, Issue 2691, Jun. 18, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Robert Lowell On Two Poets The New York Review, Volume 6, Number 8, May 12, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Sylvia Plath Lesbos The New York Review, Volume 6, Number 8, May 12, 1966
- George Steiner Dying Is an Art The Reporter, Volume 33, Number 6, Oct. 7, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Sexton, Anne. TLS to William Claire, 1 page, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Young Fisher, Alfred. ALS to William Claire, 2 pages., Oct. 25, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Hughes, Ted. ALS to William Claire, 1 page, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Porter, Katherine Anne. TLS to William Claire, 1 page., Feb. 12 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Davidson, Peter. TLS to William Claire, 1 page., Jan. 12, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Davidson, Peter. TLS to William Claire, 1 page., Jun. 15, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Drew, Elizabeth. ALS to William Claire, 1 page and envelope., Jun. 7, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Drew, Elizabeth. ALS to William Claire, 1 page., Jun. 18, 1962
- Stoianoff, Ellen A. TLS to William Claire, 1 page., Dec. 8, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Murphy, Frank. ALS to William Claire, 1 page., Aug. 18, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Murphy, Frank. ALS to William Claire, 1 page, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Murphy, Frank. ALS to William Claire, 1 page and envelope., Mar. 12, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Williams, Ann E. TLS to William Claire, 1 page., Nov. 12, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)